David Mitchell fonds
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department
- Political contemporaries, 1911 - 1982; F-56-3; 82 cm of textual records
  Series consists of records relating to W.A.C. Bennett's political contemporaries. Includes transcribed interviews, newspaper and magazine articles and correspondence. Some interview transcripts are incomplete, and some contain Mitchell's annotations.
  - Dave Barrett, 1978 - 1980; F-56-3-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 56-9)
  - W. Black 1/2, 1977; F-56-3-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 56-9)
  - W. Black 2/2, 1977 - 1978; F-56-3-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 56-9)
  - Robert W. Bonner 1/2, 1974 - 1975; F-56-3-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 56-10)
  - Robert W. Bonner 2/2, 1975 - 1982; F-56-3-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 56-10)
  - Donald Brothers, 1978; F-56-3-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 56-10)
  - Robert Browne-Clayton, 1979; F-56-3-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 56-10)
  - Gerald S. Bryson, 1957 - 1981; F-56-3-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 56-10)
  - Dan Campbell, 1964 - 1980; F-56-3-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 56-10)
  - A.E. Carlson, 1961 - 1982; F-56-3-0-0-10 (Archival box - standard 56-10)
  - Ralph Chetwynd, 1941 - 1978; F-56-3-0-0-11 (Archival box - standard 56-10)
  - William Clancey, 1964 - 1980; F-56-3-0-0-12 (Archival box - standard 56-10)
  - [no file - file below typed in duplicate], F-56-3-0-0-13 (Archival box - standard 56-10)
  - J.V. Clyne, [ca 1970] - [ca 1979]; F-56-3-0-0-14 (Archival box - standard 56-10)
  - Gerald Cross, 1977; F-56-3-0-0-15 (Archival box - standard 56-10)
  - Lloyd Detwiller, 1977; F-56-3-0-0-16 (Archival box - standard 56-10)
  - John Diefenbaker, 1978 - 1982; F-56-3-0-0-17 (Archival box - standard 56-10)
  - G. Daniel Ekman, 1978; F-56-3-0-0-18 (Archival box - standard 56-10)
  - J.F.K. English, 1974; F-56-3-0-0-19 (Archival box - standard 56-11)
  - Ted Evers, 1975 - 1980; F-56-3-0-0-20 (Archival box - standard 56-11)
  - Charles J. Ferber, 1970 - 1978; F-56-3-0-0-21 (Archival box - standard 56-11)
  - Philip A. Gaglardi, 1977 - 1978; F-56-3-0-0-22 (Archival box - standard 56-11)
  - Philip A. Gaglardi - Chapters 2-7, 1978; F-56-3-0-0-23 (Archival box - standard 56-11)
  - Philip A. Gaglardi - Chapters 8-13, 1978; F-56-3-0-0-24 (Archival box - standard 56-11)
  - Gordon Gibson Sr., 1975 - 1982; F-56-3-0-0-25 (Archival box - standard 56-11)
  - Dorothy Gow, 1978; F-56-3-0-0-26 (Archival box - standard 56-11)
  - Howard Green, 1979; F-56-3-0-0-27 (Archival box - standard 56-11)
  - Einar M. Gunderson, 1977; F-56-3-0-0-28 (Archival box - standard 56-11)
  - Randolph Harding 1/2, 1978; F-56-3-0-0-29 (Archival box - standard 56-11)
  - Randolph Harding 2/2, 1978; F-56-3-0-0-30 (Archival box - standard 56-11)
  - Arthur Helps, 1977 - 1978; F-56-3-0-0-31 (Archival box - standard 56-11)
  - Hugh L. Keenleyside, 1978; F-56-3-0-0-32 (Archival box - standard 56-11)
  - Cam Kenmuir, 1980; F-56-3-0-0-33 (Archival box - standard 56-12)
  - Gilbert Kennedy, 1978; F-56-3-0-0-34 (Archival box - standard 56-12)
  - Orvis Kennedy, 1977; F-56-3-0-0-35 (Archival box - standard 56-12)
  - Henry Landry, 1978; F-56-3-0-0-36 (Archival box - standard 56-12)
  - Keith Littler, 1975 - 1982; F-56-3-0-0-37 (Archival box - standard 56-12)
  - Ralph Loffmark, 1978 - 1979; F-56-3-0-0-38 (Archival box - standard 56-12)
  - R.C. MacDonald, 1978; F-56-3-0-0-39 (Archival box - standard 56-12)
  - Cora MaCaulay, 1980; F-56-3-0-0-40 (Archival box - standard 56-12)
  - Grace MacInnis, 1978; F-56-3-0-0-41 (Archival box - standard 56-12)
  - Grace McCarthy, 1966 - 1980; F-56-3-0-0-42 (Archival box - standard 56-12)
  - Patrick L. McGeer, 1976; F-56-3-0-0-43 (Archival box - standard 56-12)
  - Dermott McInnes, 1978; F-56-3-0-0-44 (Archival box - standard 56-12)
  - Frank McMahon, 1961 - 1964; F-56-3-0-0-45 (Archival box - standard 56-12)
  - Ernest C. Manning, 1977; F-56-3-0-0-46 (Archival box - standard 56-12)
  - O.S. Marden, 1911; F-56-3-0-0-47 (Archival box - standard 56-12)
  - Eric Martin, 1970; F-56-3-0-0-48 (Archival box - standard 56-12)
  - Joe Morris, 1980; F-56-3-0-0-49 (Archival box - standard 56-12)
  - Leo T. Nimsick, 1978; F-56-3-0-0-50 (Archival box - standard 56-12)
  - C.D. Orchard, 1960; F-56-3-0-0-51 (Archival box - standard 56-13)
  - Ray Orchard, 1978; F-56-3-0-0-52 (Archival box - standard 56-13)
  - Ralph Pashley, [ca 1970] - [ca 1979]; F-56-3-0-0-53 (Archival box - standard 56-13)
  - Thomas Dufferin Patullo - Notes, 1979 - 1980; F-56-3-0-0-54 (Archival box - standard 56-13)
  - Peer Paynter, 1977; F-56-3-0-0-55 (Archival box - standard 56-13)
  - Leslie Peterson, 1963 - 1980; F-56-3-0-0-56 (Archival box - standard 56-13)
  - Percy Richards, 1974; F-56-3-0-0-57 (Archival box - standard 56-13)
  - Cyril Shelford, 1963 - 1980; F-56-3-0-0-58 (Archival box - standard 56-13)
  - Gordon Shrum, 1974; F-56-3-0-0-59 (Archival box - standard 56-13)
  - Waldo M. Skillings, 1977 - 1981; F-56-3-0-0-60 (Archival box - standard 56-13)
  - Mel Smith, 1971 - 1978; F-56-3-0-0-61 (Archival box - standard 56-14)
  - Sidney Garfield Smith, 1960; F-56-3-0-0-62 (Archival box - standard 56-14)
  - Robert Sommers, 1956 - 1979; F-56-3-0-0-63 (Archival box - standard 56-14)
  - Robert Strachan, 1978; F-56-3-0-0-64 (Archival box - standard 56-14)
  - John A. Tames, 1978; F-56-3-0-0-65 (Archival box - standard 56-14)
  - Robert N. Thompson, 1977; F-56-3-0-0-66 (Archival box - standard 56-14)
  - Gordon Torey, 1977; F-56-3-0-0-67 (Archival box - standard 56-14)
  - Arthur J. Turner, 1973; F-56-3-0-0-68 (Archival box - standard 56-14)
  - A. Douglas Turnbull, 1974; F-56-3-0-0-69 (Archival box - standard 56-14)
  - Clarence Wallace, 1977 - 1978; F-56-3-0-0-70 (Archival box - standard 56-14)
  - Lawrence James Wallace, 1978 - 1981; F-56-3-0-0-71 (Archival box - standard 56-14)
  - Scott Wallace, 1978; F-56-3-0-0-72 (Archival box - standard 56-14)
  - Derril Warren, 1971 - 1977; F-56-3-0-0-73 (Archival box - standard 56-14)
  - Robert L. Wenman, 1978; F-56-3-0-0-74 (Archival box - standard 56-14)
  - Lyle Wicks, 1978; F-56-3-0-0-75 (Archival box - standard 56-14)
  - Ray G. Williston 1/2, 1976; F-56-3-0-0-76 (Archival box - standard 56-15)
  - Ray G. Williston 2/2, 1975; F-56-3-0-0-77 (Archival box - standard 56-15)
  - Earl Westwood, 1975; F-56-3-0-0-78 (Archival box - standard 56-15)
  - Walter Young, 1966 - 1978; F-56-3-0-0-79 (Archival box - standard 56-15)
- Political issues / Social Credit Party, 1934 - 1983; F-56-4; 38 cm of textual records
  Series consists of records relating to issues dealt with by the Bennett government and the workings of the Social Credit Party. Includes interview transcripts, copies of speeches, correspondence, newspaper and magazine articles, reports, papers, annual reports and Mitchell's notes.
  - Bank of British Columbia, 1976 - 1978; F-56-4-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 56-16)
  - B.C. Electric Takeover, 1954 - 1961; F-56-4-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 56-16)
  - British Columbia Railway, 1977 - 1979; F-56-4-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 56-16)
  - Coalition, 1941 - 1975; F-56-4-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 56-16)
  - Doukhobours, 1957 - 1979; F-56-4-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 56-16)
  - Elections, 1937 - 1976; F-56-4-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 56-16)
  - Five Regions 1/2, 1977 - 1978; F-56-4-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 56-16)
  - Five Regions 2/2, 1940 - 1970; F-56-4-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 56-16)
  - Free Trade, 1978 - 1979; F-56-4-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 56-16)
  - Davie Fulton, 1956 - 1982; F-56-4-0-0-10 (Archival box - standard 56-16)
  - Hospital Insurance, 1960 - 1978; F-56-4-0-0-11 (Archival box - standard 56-17)
  - Lord Commission, 1956; F-56-4-0-0-12 (Archival box - standard 56-17)
  - Negative Income Tax, 1978 - 1979; F-56-4-0-0-13 (Archival box - standard 56-17)
  - New Democratic Party, 1937 - 1979; F-56-4-0-0-14 (Archival box - standard 56-17)
  - The Paranoid Style, 1970 - 1976; F-56-4-0-0-15 (Archival box - standard 56-17)
  - Pensions, 1977 - 1980; F-56-4-0-0-16 (Archival box - standard 56-17)
  - Post-War Rehabilitation Council, 1943 - 1947; F-56-4-0-0-17 (Archival box - standard 56-17)
  - Power, 1962 - 1980; F-56-4-0-0-18 (Archival box - standard 56-17)
  - Social Credit Party (Alberta), 1975 - 1982; F-56-4-0-0-19 (Archival box - standard 56-17)
  - Social Credit Party (Saskatchewan), 1955 - 1983; F-56-4-0-0-20 (Archival box - standard 56-17)
  - Social Credit Party, 1952; F-56-4-0-0-21 (Archival box - standard 56-17)
  - Social Credit Party - Elections, 1952 - 1972; F-56-4-0-0-22 (Archival box - standard 56-18)
  - Social Credit Party - Year Books, 1970 - 1972; F-56-4-0-0-23 (Archival box - standard 56-18)
  - Social Credit Party - South Okanagan By-Election, 1948; F-56-4-0-0-24 (Archival box - standard 56-18)
  - Social Credit Party - Yale By-Election, 1948; F-56-4-0-0-25 (Archival box - standard 56-18)
  - Social Credit Party - Esquimalt By-Election, 1951; F-56-4-0-0-26 (Archival box - standard 56-18)
  - Social Credit Party - Young Socreds, 1964 - 1978; F-56-4-0-0-27 (Archival box - standard 56-18)
  - Social Credit Party - Miscellaneous Materials, 1934 - 1964; F-56-4-0-0-28 (Archival box - standard 56-18)
  - Social Credit Party - Bibiliography, 1975 - 1982; F-56-4-0-0-29 (Archival box - standard 56-18)
- Journal and other reference articles, 1937 - 1982; F-56-5; 16 cm of textual records
  Series consists of published and unpublished reference articles. Includes newspaper clippings, journal articles and academic papers.
  - Articles - Journals (A), 1975; F-56-5-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 56-19)
  - Articles - Journals (A), 1937 - 1972; F-56-5-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 56-19)
  - Articles - Journals (B), 1979; F-56-5-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 56-19)
  - Articles - Journals (C-H), 1952 - 1969; F-56-5-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 56-19)
  - Articles - Journals (I-N), 1948 - 1978; F-56-5-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 56-19)
  - Articles - Journals (O-S), 1962 - 1971; F-56-5-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 56-19)
  - Articles - Newspapers, 1942 - 1952; F-56-5-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 56-19)
  - Articles - Newspapers, 1961 - 1976; F-56-5-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 56-19)
  - Articles - Newspapers, 1976 - 1979; F-56-5-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 56-20)
  - Articles - Newspapers, 1969 - 1982; F-56-5-0-0-10 (Archival box - standard 56-20)
  - Articles - Newspapers - French, 1960; F-56-5-0-0-11 (Archival box - standard 56-20)
- Other Bennett biographies, 1960 - 1985; F-56-6; 7 cm of textual records
  Series consists of records relating to biographies of W.A.C. Bennett and his family. Includes a family history written by Bennett's sister Cora (Bennett) Macaulay, chapter outlines for Mitchell's book, an unpublished draft biography by Bennett's daughter, Anita Tozer, and reviews of other published biographies.
  - W.A.C. Bennett Biographies - Cora MaCaulay, 1978; F-56-6-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 56-20)
  - W.A.C. Bennett Biographies - David J. Mitchell, [ca 1985]; F-56-6-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 56-20)
  - W.A.C. Bennett Biographies - Radio Chim, [ca 1985]; F-56-6-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 56-20)
  - W.A.C. Bennett Biographies - Rosemary Neering, [ca 1985]; F-56-6-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 56-20)
  - W.A.C. Bennett Biographies - Anita Tozer, [ca 1985]; F-56-6-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 56-20)
  - W.A.C. Bennett Biographies - Anita Tozer, [ca 1985]; F-56-6-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 56-20)
  - W.A.C. Bennett Biographies - Book Reviews, 1960 - 1980; F-56-6-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 56-20)
- Graphic material, 1952 - 1982; F-56-7; 2 cm of textual records 62 photographs 4 copy negatives; Physical description: 42 photographs located in F-56-7-0-1 Physical description: 20 photographs located in F-56-7-0-2
  Series consists of graphic material gathered by David Mitchell for his book. Includes photographs, magazine and newspaper articles, correspondence regarding photograph orders and permissions, and a copy of the British Columbia Centennial '71 Committee's Premiers Since Confederation which includes 20 5x7 photographs of the provinces' premiers.
  - Graphic material, 1952 - 1982; F-56-7-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 56-20)
    Textual records; Photographic materials
  - Graphic material, 1971; F-56-7-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 56-20)